Guide to the Leverich Family Papers 1817-1937 (Bulk 1820-1890) MS 381
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Business/Financial Papers, 1818, 1825-1890
  - Subseries 2: Bills, Receipts, Invoices, Transferable Orders for Cotton, Payrolls, Charges, 1825-1890
    - Bills, Receipts, Invoices, 1889 Jan. - 1889 Jul. (Offsite-box 37, Folder 8)
    - Bills, Receipts, Invoices, 1889 Aug. - 1889 Dec. (Offsite-box 38, Folder 1)
    - Bills, Receipts, Invoices, [1880-1890] (Offsite-box 38, Folder 2)
    - Bills, Receipts, Invoices, 1890 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 3)
    - Bills, Receipts, Invoices, undated (Offsite-box 38, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3: Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1826-1890
    Contains material that concerns the profit and loss from completed transactions, as would be entered into an account book, and usually concern the recording of transactions over an extended period of time. Accounts refer to Account Sales and Sales. Account Sales records the overall, unitemized credits and debits of perhaps hundreds of transactions. Sales record a series of transactions regarding a single shipment of goods. Statements are similar to account sales but may record transactions with multiple firms, or may record only specific types of transactions with the same firm. Trial balances are a preliminary balancing of accounts created prior to final entry in the ledger.
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances: "Account Sales to January 1832", 1828-1832 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 5)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances: "Acc. Sales 1838", 1838 Mar. - 1838 Dec. (Offsite-box 38, Folder 6)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1826-1839 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 7)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1840-1846 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 8)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1847-1849 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 9)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1850-1855 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 10)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1856-1857 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 1)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1858-1859 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 2)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1860-1865 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 3)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1866-1868 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 4)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1869-1871 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 5)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1872-1874 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 6)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1875-1876 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 1)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1877-1879 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 2)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, [1870-1880] (Offsite-box 40, Folder 3)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1880-1882 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 4)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1884-1889 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 5)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, [1880-1890] (Offsite-box 40, Folder 6)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, 1890 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 7)
    - Accounts, Statements, Tabulations, Trial Balances, undated (Offsite-box 40, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 4: Bills of Lading/Freight Receipts, 1827-1889
    Contains material having to do with the shipment or receipt of goods. Bills of lading are itemized lists of goods shipped by a given firm via a given carrier. Freight receipts are itemized lists of goods received from a given firm via a given carrier. Some of the carriers with whom the Leveriches dealt and who are present in the collection are: Cromwell's New York and New Orleans Steamship Line; New York Mail Steamship Company; The Union R.R. and Transportation Company; Old Dominion Steamship Co.; and the Seaboard Inland Air-line; among many others. Also included with this material is a folder containing ship charters (1839, 1858-1861).
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts: "Bills of Lading Outward to 1833", 1827 Jul. - 1829 Mar. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 9)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts: "Bills of Lading Inward 1827 to 1833", 1828 Nov. - 1829 Jul. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 10)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts: "Bills of Lading Outward to 1833", 1829 Nov. - 1830 Oct. (Offsite-box 40, Folder 11)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts: "Bills of Lading. Inward 1827 to 1833", 1830 Jan. - 1831 Sept. (Offsite-box 41, Folder 1)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts: "Bills of Lading Outward to 1833", 1831 Jan. - 1832 Apr. (Offsite-box 41, Folder 2)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts: "Bills Lading 1835 to 1836", 1835 Feb. - 1836 Jan. (Offsite-box 41, Folder 3)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts: "Bills Lading 1837-1838", 1837 Jan. - 1838 Nov. (Offsite-box 41, Folder 4)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1830-1838 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 5)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1849 Aug. - 1851 Jan. (Offsite-box 41, Folder 6)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1857 Nov. - 1859 Dec. (Offsite-box 41, Folder 7)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1860-1864 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 1)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1865 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 2)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1866 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 3)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1867 Jan. - 1867 Jun. (Offsite-box 42, Folder 4)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1867 Jul. - 1867 Dec. (Offsite-box 42, Folder 5)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1868 Jan. - 1868 Sept. (Offsite-box 42, Folder 6)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1868 Oct. - 1868 Dec. (Offsite-box 43, Folder 1)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1869 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 2)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1870 Jan. - 1870 Aug. (Offsite-box 43, Folder 3)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1870 Sept. - 1870 Dec. (Offsite-box 43, Folder 4)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1871 Jan. - 1871 Oct. (Offsite-box 43, Folder 5)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1871 Nov. - 1871 Dec. (Offsite-box 43, Folder 6)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1872 Jan. - 1872 Sept. (Offsite-box 44, Folder 1)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1872 Oct. - 1872 Dec. (Offsite-box 44, Folder 2)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1873 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 3)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1874 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 4)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1875 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 5)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1876 1878 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 6)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, 1885-1889 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 7)
    - Bills of Lading/ Freight Receipts, undated (Offsite-box 44, Folder 8)
    - Ship Charters, 1837 1858-1861 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 5: Checks, Notes, Exchanges, 1827-1888
    Contains commercial paper; that is, everything from personal checks to negotiable financial instruments. Checks are simple bank checks. Notes are promises by one party to pay a given sum of money to another. Exchanges are re-negotiable instruments that can be traded in their own right. The loose checks, notes, and exchanges are arranged semi-chronologically, roughly grouped by banking entity. This section also includes one box of 32 bankbooks spanning 1827-1885, and 1 box of 7 checkbooks spanning 1827-1887. Much of the material relates to the Bank of New York.
    - Checks, Notes, Exchanges, 1827-1888 (Offsite-box 45, Folder unknown container)
    - Checks, Notes, Exchanges, 1827-1863 (Offsite-box 46, Folder unknown container)
    - Checks, Notes, Exchanges, 1859-1873 (Offsite-box 47, Folder unknown container)
    - Checks, Notes, Exchanges, 1829-1835, 1847-1849, 1867-1881 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 1)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Henry S. Leverich with Merchants Bank", 1827-1830 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Henry S. Leverich with New York Bank", 1828-1831 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Note Book Henry S. Leverich with New York Bank", 1828-1840 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Henry S. Leverich with Bank of New York", 1831-1837 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Henry S. Leverich with Bank of New York", 1837-1839 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Notes. Henry S. Leverich in Account with the Bank of the State of New York", 1838 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Henry S. Leverich. Bank of New York", 1840-1844 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Bank of New York in a/c with Henry S. Leverich", 1844-1846 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Bank of New York with Henry S. Leverich", 1846-1847 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Bank of New-York in a/c with H. S. Leverich", 1847-1851 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Bank of New-York with H. S. Leverich", 1851-1852 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Bank of New-York in Account with H. S. Leverich", 1853-1856 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Bank of New-York in Account with Henry S. Leverich", 1859-1862 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Charles P. Leverich: "Bank of New-York in Account with C. P. Leverich", 1861-1862 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Charles P. Leverich: "Bank of New-York in Account with C. P. Leverich", 1863 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Charles P. Leverich: "Bank of New-York in Account with C. P. Leverich", 1863-1864 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Bank of New-York in Account with Leverich & Co.", 1865-1867 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Bank of New-York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Co.", 1867-1868 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Bank of New-York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Compy. 171 Water St.", 1868-1869 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Bank of New-York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Compy.", 1869-1870 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Bank of New-York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Co.", 1870-1871 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Bank of New York National Banking Association in Gold Account with Leverich & Co.", 1870-1877 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Bank of New York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Co.", 1871-1873 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Collections in Bank of New York for Leverich & Co. 1872", 1872-1877 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: " Bank of New York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Co.", 1875-1877 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Bank of New York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Co. 111 Pearl St.", 1877-1878 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "N. O. Canal & Banking Co. in Account with Edward Leverich", 1881-1884 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Bank of America in Account with Mrs. Annie F. Leverich 3 Dec. 1883 to", 1883-1885 (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Checks. Bank of New York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Co.", undated (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Checks. Bank of New York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Co.", undated (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Checks. Bank of New-York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Co.", undated (Offsite-box 51)
    - Leverich & Co.: "Checks. Bank of New York National Banking Association in Account with Leverich & Co.", undated (Offsite-box 51)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "Merchants Bank Checks, H.S.L." (Check Book), 1827-1830 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Henry S. Leverich: "New York Bank Checks" (Check Book), 1828-1831 (Offsite-box 52)
    - [Charles P. Leverich]: "New York Checks" (Check Book), 1838-1847 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Charles P. Leverich: "Bank of New York Checks, C.P.L." (Check Book), 1854-1858 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Charles P. Leverich: "B'K. N.Y. Checks, C.P.L." (Check Book), 1858-1861 (Offsite-box 52)
    - [Leverich & Co.]: "[Marine National Bank]" (Check Book), 1875 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Annie Leverich: "[The Farmer's Loan and Trust Company]" (Check book), 1887 (Offsite-box 52)
  - Subseries 6: Prices Current, Circulars, Catalogues & Notices, 1831-1890
    Contains a few folders of the aforementioned. The prices current relate to cotton, commodities, and stock prices in New Orleans and New York as well as overseas markets in Liverpool, Bremen, Antwerp, and Canton. Circulars, catalogues and notices relate to sugar and molasses, livestock, and sundry items.
    - Circulars & Price Currents, 1831-1890 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 2)
    - Catalogues & Notices, undated (Offsite-box 48, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 7: Scrap & Fragments, undated
    Refer to notations, computations, drafts of trial balances, pieces of documents, and other such items.
    - Business Scrap, [1870-1880] (Offsite-box 48, Folder 4)
    - Business Scrap, undated (Offsite-box 48, Folder 5)
- Series III. Legal, Taxes, Insurance, 1817, 1824-1889
  This series contains a variety of legal documents, forms and maps including: contracts, wills, titles, indentures, deeds, trial transcripts, depositions, powers of attorney, tax and insurance forms, maps and surveys. The material is arranged by subject and then chronologically within folders. Some of the earliest material in this series relates to the Estate of Jesse Leverich (probably Col. Edward Leverich's brother), Newtown, New York and dates from the 1820's to the 1840's. These documents detail the estate's finances and land holdings. There is also some genealogical information contained in this material.
  The "General" folder includes legal documents from Leverich and non-Leverich Family members. Notable non-Leverich Family members include the Porter, Gustine, and Schuchardt families. The materials in the "General" folder span the years 1830-1889, with a single item dating from 1817. These documents consist of power of attorney forms, contracts, wills, articles of association, articles of incorporation, and other legal materials. Of special interest is the last will and testament of James Porter, 1848, owner of the Oak Lawn Plantation. Included in this folder is an "Abstract of Title to the Homestead of Late Henry S. Leverich at Newtown, Queens County, Long Island," ca. 1885. There are also arbitration documents from the 1860's and 1870's for the New York Cotton Exchange.
  Much of the legal material relating to the Oak Lawn Plantation dates from the 1870's and 1880's and deals with two lawsuits involving Annie F. Leverich. Following the death of her husband Edward Leverich in 1886, Annie Leverich became involved in legal suits with the Burdon Central Sugar Refinery. At issue was Annie Leverich's contractual obligation to provide the refinery with Oak Lawn's crops from the years 1886 to 1889. The first case, Henry J. Davison v. Mrs. Annie F. Leverich, 1887, alleges Annie's failure to meet the requirements of the contract. In 1888, Annie Leverich countersues Mr. Davison's company, The Burdon Central Sugar Refinery, for negligence in the handling of the sugar cane that she had supplied to them in 1886. The trial transcripts, depositions, and notes of Annie Leverich and her confidante George Payne, provide insight into the management of the plantation in the years following the Civil War and the legal status of women as property owners at that time.
  Other items of note relating to Oak Lawn include announcements advertising the sale of the plantation in 1888; inventories of the contents of the house; and promissory notes related to tenants and the hiring of workers. Among the Oak Lawn material can be found maps and drawings of the Oak Lawn and Dogberry plantations and their surrounding areas. The drawings include layout of crops.
  Taxation materials also make up a part of this series, these include property and utility tax documents, 1838-1886 non-inclusive, the bulk of which are for properties in New York; business permits from the U.S. Internal Revenue Collectors Office, 1863-1868; and customs forms, 1835-1838.
  Materials relating to insurance and insurance policies, 1854-1875, can also be found in this series. Insurance materials include a register, 1866-1875, and record books for the Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company, 1854-1876; Long Island Insurance Co., 1865-1874; Niagara Fire Insurance Company; United States Fire Insurance Company, 1866; and the American Fire Insurance Co., 1865-1866.
  Maps and surveys of the Newtown, New York area can be found in a separate folder in the series.
  - Legal: General, 1817, 1830-1889, undated (Offsite-box 48, Folder 6)
  - Legal: Estate of Jesse Leverich, 1824-1835, 1839-1842 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 7)
  - Legal: Oak Lawn, 1848, 1873, 1886-1888 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 1)
  - Legal: Henry J. Davison v. Annie F. Leverich, 1886-1889 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 2)
  - Legal: Henry J. Davison v. Annie F. Leverich, 1886-1889 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 3)
  - Legal: Henry J. Davison v. Annie F. Leverich, 1886-1889 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 4)
  - Legal: Annie F. Leverich v. Burdon Central Sugar Refinery, 1888 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 5)
  - Legal: Annie F. Leverich v. Burdon Central Sugar Refinery, 1888 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 6)
  - Taxes: Property & Utility, 1838, 1848-1874, 1878, 1886 (Offsite-box 49, Folder 7)
  - Taxes: Business Permits, 1863-1868 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 1)
  - Taxes: Customs, 1835-1838 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 2)
  - Insurance, 1861-1875 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 3)
  - Maps & Surveys: New York (Offsite-box 50, Folder 4)
  - "American Fire Insurance Co. 48 Wall st. with Leverich & Co. 35,616", 1865-1866 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "United States Fire Insurance Co. No. 69 Wall Street. In Account with Leverich & Co.", 1866 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Open Policy Niagara Fire Ins. Co. with Leverich & Co.", 1867 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "American Fire Insurance Co. 48 Wall Street with Leverich & Co.", undated (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Open Policy Long Island Ins. Co. No. 48 Wall st. with Leverich & Co.", 1871-1874 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Long Island Insurance Co. with Leverich & Co.", 1865-1867 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Open Policy Long Island Ins. Co. No. 48 Wall st. with Leverich & Co.", 1867 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company", undated (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company", 1872-1874 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company", 1871-1872 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company Outward", 1870-1876 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company. Leverich & Co. Homeward", 1870-1871 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company [Inward]", 1869-1870 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Attacapas Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company", 1854-1855 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Outward Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company", 1854-1860 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Inward Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company", 1854-1864 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company Outward", 1860-1864 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company", 1865-1866 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company Inward", 1866-1868 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company Outward", 1866-1870 (Offsite-box 53)
  - "Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company. Leverich & Co. Homeward--Inward", 1868-1869 (Offsite-box 53)
- Series IV. Family Memorabilia, 1850s-1903, undated
  The Family Memorabilia series consists of family-related and miscellaneous material. The series includes children's writings including Edward Leverich's essays from when he was in military school in Sing Sing, New York in the 1850's; and a "newspaper" and a poetry booklet composed by M.D.L. [Margaret Duncan Leverich] circa 1888. The series also contains an engagement book (1899-1903) also belonging to "MDL". The series also contains newspaper clipped and handwritten recipes for food and medicines, as well as miscellaneous newspaper clippings and writings.
  There are two carte-de-visite photographs. The photographs may be those of Henry S. Leverich and Margaret Leverich or Mary Leverich.
  - [unittitle added: see error report]
    - String (in envelope) (Offsite-box 56)
    - String from checks, notes, exchanges (in envelope) (Offsite-box 56)
    - Oversized material (Folder Oversize)
    - Fragile documents [restricted] (Offsite-box 57)
    - Fragile documents [restricted] (Offsite-box 58)
  - Children's Writings, 1853-1855, 1888, undated (Offsite-box 50, Folder 5)
  - Engagement Book (Party Planner) of M[argaret] D[uncan] L[everich], 1899-1903 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 6)
  - Memorial: Edward Leverich, 1886 (Offsite-box 50, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings & Notes, undated (Offsite-box 50, Folder 8)
  - Recipes, undated (Offsite-box 50, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, undated (Offsite-box 50, Folder 10)
  - Personal Writings, undated (Offsite-box 50, Folder 11)
  - Placards, undated (Offsite-box 50, Folder 12)
  - Placards, Filing Labels, undated (Offsite-box 50, Folder 13)
  - Rice (in envelope) (Offsite-box 56)
  - Stamps (in envelope) (Offsite-box 56)